A Finding Aid to the William Page and Page Family Papers, 1815-1947, bulk 1843-1892, in the Archives of American Art AAA.pagewill
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1815-1942, undated; Series 2; (Boxes 1-4, 9-10; 3.2 linear feet)
  - General Correspondence, 1815-1942, undated; 2.1
    Maquay, George A.: 1853
    Marrell, J.H.: 1871
    Martin, Charles F.: 1887-1888
    Martin, Mrs. C.L.: 1877, 1885, 1887
    Martin, Louise P.: 1885
    Martin, ?H.H.: 1872
    Maston, William H.: 1866
    Mead, Mary V.: 1877, 1882, undated
    Menger, Louis R.: 1880, 1887
    Merchant, Daniel M.: 1868
    Metcalf, Arthur: 1884
    Millner, J.B.: 1877
    Minturn, Robert B.: 1861, undated
    Moulton, Charles: 1886
    Moulton, Francis: 1872
    Munn and Co.: 1861
    Murphy, Charles: 1888
    Naramore, E.M.: 1875
    Neal, John: 1855
    Newton, O.L.: 1864
    Nichols, Abel: 1857
    Nichols, Florence: 1857
    Nichols, George Ward: 1857
    Norris, J. Parker: 1870, 1873-1877, undated
    Norton, Catherine: 1874, 1878, undated
    Nutting, Mary O.: 1883
    O'Donovan, W.R.: 1877, 1886, 1890-1891, undated
    Olmsted, Bertha: 1853-1854, 1856-1857, 1860
    Olmsted, Frederick Law: 1868-1869
    Olmsted, John H.: 1851, 1853-1854
    Olmsted, Mary A.: 1850, 1853-1854, 1874, 1877, undated
    Osborne, Mary: undated
    Ostrander, Nathaniel J.: 1885
    Pakenham, N.: 1851
    Pardue, Charles Inslee: 1873
    Parkhurst, Henry M.: 1865-1866
    Partridge, James R.: 1862
    Patterson, F.B.: 1874
    Peabody, Cornelia Marshall: undated
    Peck, J.: 1854
    Peet, Eileen: 1884
    Pentecost, Hugh O.: 1890
    Perkins, T.B.: 1872
    Perry, Enoch Wood: 1870, 1873, 1877-1878, 1882-1884, 1886, 1902, undated
    Phillips, E.O.: 1876
    Phillips, Wendell: undated
    Powers, H.N.: 1876
    Putnam, G.P.: 1866
    Quick, Addie T.: 1872
    Rawson, Charlotte: 1886, 1888
    Raymond, George: 1886
    Ream, Vinnie: undated
    Reinhart, B.F.: 1873
    Rice, Alexander H.; 1882-1883
    Richards, T. Addision: 1882, 1886 (see also the letters used as evidence in Page's probate trial; Series 4)
    Richmond, Victoria and J.W.B.: 1883, 1886
    Rider, George S.J.: 1868
    Ridner, Caroline: 1885, 1887
    Rively, Mary: 1886-1887
    Robertson, Ann Elize Worcester: 1877
    Robinson, A.S.: 1852-1853, 1855, 1862
    Robinson, E.: 1874
    Robinson, George C.: 1868, undated
    Robinson, Mrs. Jennie: 1870
    Robinson, M.C.: 1853
    Robinson, W.H.: 1875-1876
    Rogers, John: undated
    Rogers, W.K.: 1877
    Rose, J.W.: 1882
    ?Rossel: 1878
    Ruggles, Edward: 1861
    Sanborn, ?O.H.: 1868
    Sartain, John: 1875
    Schultz, E.A.: 1873
    Schuyler, Louisa Lee: 1877
    Schwab, Charles M.: 1906
    Scott, Frank H.: 1875
    Scott, Julian: 1874
    Scranton, William Walker: 1874-1875, 1877-1879, 187?, 1880-1881
    Scribner editors: 1879
    Searle, L.: undated
    Sellstedt, L.G.: 1863-1864, undated
    Shaw, Anna K: 1863, undated
    Shaw, Francis George: 1850-1851, 1853-1855, 1859, 1861, 1863-1864, 1872-1874, 1876-1877, 1880-1881, undated (see also letters used as evidence in Page's probate trial; Series 4)
    Shaw, Sarah B.: 1877, 1879, 1881, 1883, 1885-1889, 1892, undated
    Shegogue, J.H.: 1848
    Shelton, W.H.: 1905
    Shinn, Earl: 1873
    Shipman, Andrew: 1892
    Shipman, Frank: 1886
    Shipman, Mary C.: 1886, undated
    Skinner, Mabel R.: 1879
    Smith, Charles E.: 1868
    Smith, J. Eustace: 1884
    Southland, William D.: 1886
    Spencer, L: 1862
    Sperry, Watson: 1880
    Spring, Jeanie: 1861
    Spring, Marcus: 1867, 1869, 1872
    Spring, R.B.: undated
    Spring, Rebecca: 1886
    Stafford, John: 1864, 1877
    Stafford, O.H.: 1864
    Stark, William and Madelaine: 1858, 1860-1862
    Stebbins, A.: 1869
    Stenton, Josephine: 1872
    Stoddard, W.O.: 1870
    Storrs, R.S.: 1870
    Story, Mr. and Mrs. William Wetmore: 1850, undated
    Sturgis, Robert: 1870, 1873, undated
    Sturgis, Russell: 1874-1875, 1879, 1881
    Suydam, W.A.: 1883
    Taylor, Charles J.: 1869
    Thayer, A.H.: 1890, undated
    Thayer, William Henry: undated
    Thompson, E.C.: 1863
    Thompson, Launt: 1872
    Tilton, Theodore: 1868-1872
    Torry, C.P.: 1869
    Varnum, Joseph b.: 1875
    Vaughn, Virginia: 1854
    Vaulchaick, S.W.: 1873
    Vlymer, Alice: 1884
    Wainwright, C.S.: undated
    Wales, George: 1856
    Wall, J.W.: undated
    War Department: 1877
    Ward, J.Q.A.: 1870, 1872, 1873
    Ward, Sam S.: 1850
    Washburn, B. Davis: 1868
    Watson, Fred: 1882
    Watson, J.W.: 1886, 1890
    Watts, Edmund: 1875, 1887-1889, 1892, 1903, 1907, undated
    Weir, ?J or G.F.: 1871, 1874, 1876
    Welby, Edgar: 1856
    Weston, Eduard Payson: 1863
    Weston, Theodore: 1871
    Whiting, Julia D.: 1879
    Whittingham, Jane: 1881
    Wild, Hamilton G.: 1851, undated
    Wilds, Howard Payson: 1874
    Williams, M.W.: 1857
    ?Wills (Wells?), Theodore: 1877-1878
    Wilmarth, L.E.: 1874, 1877
    Winthrop, Robert C.: 1850
    Wood, T.W.: 1880
    World's Fair St. Louis: 1904
    Wright, George F.: undated
    - General Correspondence, 1815-1829; (Oversized items housed in Box 9, sol) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - General Correspondence, 1830-1835 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - General Correspondence, 1841-1847 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - General Correspondence, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - General Correspondence, 1849 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - General Correspondence, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - General Correspondence, 1851; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
    - General Correspondence, 1852; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 18-19)
    - General Correspondence, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - General Correspondence, 1854 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - General Correspondence, 1855 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - General Correspondence, 1856 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - General Correspondence, 1857 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - General Correspondence, 1858-1859, 185- (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - General Correspondence, 1860 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - General Correspondence, 1861; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
    - General Correspondence, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - General Correspondence, 1863; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 30-31)
    - General Correspondence, 1864 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - General Correspondence, 1865 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - General Correspondence, 1866 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - General Correspondence, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - General Correspondence, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - General Correspondence, 1869 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - General Correspondence, 1870 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - General Correspondence, 1871 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - General Correspondence, 1872 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - General Correspondence, 1873; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 41-42)
    - General Correspondence, 1874; (4 folders) (Box 1, Folder 43-46)
    - General Correspondence, 1875; (3 folders) (Box 1, Folder 47-49)
    - General Correspondence, 1876; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 50-51)
    - General Correspondence, 1877; (3 folders; Oversized items housed in Box 10, OV) (Box 1, Folder 52-54)
    - General Correspondence, 1878; (2 folders) (Box 1, Folder 55-56)
    - General Correspondence, 1879 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - General Correspondence, 187-; (Oversized items housed in Box 10, OV) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - General Correspondence, 1881; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
    - General Correspondence, 1881; (2 folders) (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
    - General Correspondence, 1882; (10 folders) (Box 2, Folder 7-16)
    - General Correspondence, 1883; (10 folders) (Box 2, Folder 17-26)
    - General Correspondence, 1884; (6 folders) (Box 2, Folder 27-32)
    - General Correspondence, 1885; (8 folders) (Box 2, Folder 33-40)
    - General Correspondence, 1886; (15 folders) (Box 2, Folder 41-55)
    - General Correspondence, 1887; (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
    - General Correspondence, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 5-7)
    - General Correspondence, 1889; (4 folders) (Box 3, Folder 8-11)
    - General Correspondence, 188- (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - General Correspondence, 1890; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 13-15)
    - General Correspondence, 1891; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 16-17)
    - General Correspondence, 1892; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 18-19)
    - General Correspondence, 1893; (3 folders) (Box 3, Folder 20-22)
    - General Correspondence, 1894; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
    - General Correspondence, 1895-1897 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - General Correspondence, 1899; (2 folders) (Box 3, Folder 26-27)
    - General Correspondence, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - General Correspondence, 1901-1902 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - General Correspondence, 1903-1905 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - General Correspondence, 1906 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - General Correspondence, 1907-1917 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - General Correspondence, 1900, 1919-1920 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - General Correspondence, 1928-1932, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Undated Correspondence (Box 3)
      - Allen, Elizabeth Akers, undated (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Bartlett, C.E., undated (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Beecher, Thomas K., undated (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Briggs, Charlotte 'Sharly' to Candace 'Dace' Page, undated (Box 3, Folder 38-43)
      - Briggs, Charlotte 'Sharly' to Miscellaneous Page Family, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - Miscellaneous A-B, undated (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Carter, Susan N., undated (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - Miscellaneous C-D, undated (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - Fields, Annie, undated (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - Hall, Anna Maria, undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - Hitchcock, M.M., undated (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - Miscellaneous E-H, undated (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - Linton, W.J., undated (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - Lowell, Josephine S., undated (Box 3, Folder 53)
      - Mead, Mary V., undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - Minturn, Robert B., undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - Olmsted, Mary A., undated (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - Miscellaneous J-O, undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
      - Page, William, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
      - Page, Sophia Candace (wife), undated; (2 folders; oversized items housed in Box 9, sol) (Box 3, Folder 59-60)
      - Page, Candace, Sophia S., and Mary (daughters), undated (Box 3, Folder 61)
      - Page, James L. and George (sons), undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
      - Page, William Stevens (son), undated (Box 3, Folder 63)
      - Page Watson, Emma (daughter), undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
      - Perry, Enoch Wood, undated (Box 3, Folder 65)
      - Phillips, Wendell, undated (Box 3, Folder 66)
      - Miscellaneous P, undated (Box 3, Folder 67)
      - Shaw, Francis George, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Shaw, Sarah B., undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Stevens, B. Frank, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Stevens, Mary, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Stevens, Simon, undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous R-S, undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Miscellaneous T-W, undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - First Names or Initials Only, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Unsigned Letters, or Illegible Signatures, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Unsigned Letter Fragments, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Envelopes, 1850-1879 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Envelopes, 1882-1894 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Envelopes, 1900, 1919, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Oversized Correspondence (Items scanned with Box 1, f10 and Box 3, f60) (Box 9 (sol))
    - Oversized Correspondence (Items scanned with Box 1, f5? and Box 2, f2) (Box 10 (OV))
  - Charles Frederick Briggs Correspondence, 1843-1846, undated; 2.2
    Letters in this series are from writer and editor Charles Frederick Briggs to William Page and to poet James Russell Lowell from the mid-1840s. A draft of a single letter from Page to Briggs is also found. Briggs' lengthy letters discuss personal matters, matters relating to Briggs' publishing projects, current political figures, writings by Lowell and Page, and theoretical ideas about literature and art. Also found are two manuscripts of Briggs' comedic poems based on the character of Harry Franco, enclosed in letters to Lowell (1843) and Page (undated). Scattered, brief letters from Briggs to Page from a later period can be found in General Correspondence.
    - Charles Frederick Briggs to James Russell Lowell, 1843-1845; (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 14-16)
    - Charles Frederick Briggs to William Page, 1843-1846, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 17-18)
    - Draft of Letter from William Page to Charles Frederick Briggs, 1845 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Sophia Candace Stevens and Stephen W. Hitchcock Correspondence, 1847-1852; 2.3; (Not scanned)
    Letters in this series are between Sophia (then Stevens) and her first husband, Stephen W. Hitchcock, whose brief marriage lasted from 1851 to 1852, when Hitchcock died. Content of letters is of a personal nature. Letters in the first two folders were sewn together, and others appear to have been sewn together at one time. These letters appear to have been used as legal evidence in an unspecified trial, perhaps the contestation of William Page's will in 1886-1887. For additional documents related to legal matters, see Personal Business Records. Additional materials related to her first marriage are found in Sophia Page's writings.
    - Letters from Stephen Hitchcock to Sophia Stevens, 1847-1850; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
    - Letters from Sophia Stevens to Stephen Hitchcock, 1849-1850(not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Stephen Hitchcock and Sophia Stevens Correspondence, 1850-1852; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 4, Folder 23-24)
- Notes and Writings, 1839-1888, 1949, undated; Series 3; (Boxes 4-5, OV 10; 1.3 linear feet)
  This series contains essays, lectures, notes, notebooks, diaries, and poems written by William Page, Sophia Page, their family and associates. William Page's writings include handwritten essays and lectures on art subjects, annotated page proofs of published articles, notes, notebooks, and poetry. The extensive writings of Page's wife, Sophia Candace Page, include multiple revisions of her husband's essays and lectures as well as her own writings, including a series of travel essays written in the 1850s and published in the New York Tribune and other newspapers. Clippings of her columns are found in Printed Materials. Writings by the Page's children and Sophia Page's first husband, Stephen W. Hitchcock, are also found. The subject of writings in this series are described in greater detail in the folder list, below. Titles listed in quotation marks are taken from the original documents.
  The papers are interspersed with notes written by Page's son, granddaughter, and biographer, Joshua Taylor, about items found within the collection. Joshua Taylor conducted research in a portion of the Page papers around 1949, and the papers include a list of the manuscripts he identified, filed under his name. Taylor's notes for individual items are filed with the manuscripts they describe. Other notes written by Taylor are found with Sophia Page's large notebook and letter book of the 1860s to 1880s.
  Authorship of writings in this series is complicated by Sophia Page's effort to edit and compile her husband's writings for publication in the late 1870s. Multiple versions and fragments of William Page's essays and lectures therefore exist in Sophia Page's handwriting and other handwritings, possibly of the Page children and Rose Durfee of the National Academy, who assisted Sophia Page in her efforts. Because of Taylor's observation that Sophia Page's versions of these writings contain substantial paraphrasing and additions, they have been filed under her name. Manuscripts of works attributed to William Page, but which appear to be in Sophia Page's handwriting, are filed with William Page's writings. Other items written by William Page have been annotated by Sophia Page. The nature of Sophia and William Page's collaboration on these writings is unknown.
  Additional notes are found in Biographical Materials, Personal Business Records, and Artwork. See series descriptions for further details.
  - William Page (Box 4)
    - William Page Essays (Box 4)
      - On James Russell Lowell, circa 1843-1844 (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - "The Art and Use of Color in Imitation in Painting", circa 1845 (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - "Modern Painters by a Graduate of Oxford", after 1848 (Box 4, Folder 27)
        (Review by Page of John Ruskin publication)
      - On Italian Painting, circa 1860 (Box 4, Folder 28)
      - "The Proportions of the Human Figure", circa 1860 (Box 4, Folder 29)
      - On Shakespeare's Portraits, 1875, undated; (Oversized items housed in Box 10, OV) (Box 4, Folder 30)
        (Fragments)
      - "The Measure of a Man", circa 1879; (Oversized items housed in Box 10, OV) (Box 4, Folder 31)
      - "Coloring in Painting", undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
      - On Color Theory, undated (Box 4, Folder 33)
      - "The Second Part or Cause", undated (Box 4, Folder 34)
    - William Page Lectures (Box 4)
      - On Portraits of Shakespeare, 1868, undated (Box 4, Folder 35)
      - On Shakespeare Death Mask, 1868-1874 (Box 4, Folder 36)
      - "The Theory and Practice of Art", circa 1870s; (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 37-39)
        (A series of three lectures)
      - Second Lecture Series, circa 1870s; (3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 40-42)
      - "Finite Art the Image of Infinite Creation", 1872; (Oversized items housed in Box 10, OV) (Box 4, Folder 43)
      - National Academy of Design Lecture, undated (Box 4, Folder 44)
        (Fragment)
      - From "Art and Scope" Series, undated; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 45-46)
    - William Page Essays and Lectures, Miscellaneous Fragments, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - William Page Appointment Book, 1869 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - William Page Notebook, 1841, 1865, undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
      (Two entries from 1841 on portraits of Mrs. Morris and Mrs. Dougherty, notes on color, journal entries from 1865, and one entry in a child's writing)
    - William Page Notebook, Poetry, 1854-1859 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    - William Page Notebook, 1856, undated (Box 4, Folder 51)
      (Lengthy essays on art subjects in both Sophia and William Page's handwriting)
    - William Page Notebook, circa 1859 (Box 4, Folder 52)
      (A poem, letters to the Shaws and the Brownings, a biographical note, and an essay on the Venus of Titian and the Venus of Page)
    - William Page Notebook, undated (Box 4, Folder 53)
      (contains essays on art, notes on an exhibition of watercolors in London, and other art-related notes)
    - Notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 54)
    - Poems, 1850, undated (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Sophia Page (Box 4)
    - Sophia Page Drafts of Catalogs, 1867, undated (Box 4, Folder 56)
    - Compilations of William Page Writings (Box 4)
      - "Art and Scope" Numbers 1, 2, 3, circa 1879 (Box 4, Folder 57)
      - "No. 1, Art and Scope,", circa 1879 (Box 4, Folder 58)
      - "No. 3, Artists Not Writers,", circa 1879 (Box 4, Folder 59)
      - "No. 4, Titian,", circa 1879 (Box 4, Folder 60)
      - "No. 5, Quality in Painting and Portraiture and the Means of Rendering It,", circa 1879 (Box 4, Folder 61)
      - "No. 6, Nature and Means of Paralleling it in Painting,", circa 1879 (Box 4, Folder 62)
      - "No. 7, The Artist and His Conceits,", circa 1879 (Box 4, Folder 63)
      - "Studio Talks, No. 1-5,", circa 1879; (2 folders) (Box 4, Folder 64-65)
        "Art and Scope"
        "Quality in Painting"
        "Artists Not Writers"
        "Titian"
        "Quality in Landscape and Portraiture"
      - "The Measure of a Man,", circa 1879; (Oversized items housed in Box 10, OV) (Box 4, Folder 66)
      - "Method in Art,", circa 1879 (Box 4, Folder 67)
      - On Copying Titian's Venus, circa 1878 (Box 4, Folder 68)
      - On Titian, undated (Box 4, Folder 69)
      - Miscellaneous Fragments, late 1870s; (7 folders; oversized items housed in Box 10, OV) (Box 4, Folder 70-76)
        (Content repetitive with compilations above)
    - Sophia Page Essays (Box 5)
      - On Paris, 1854, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - On Rome and Monte Carlo, 1857 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - On Page's Painting "Venus Guiding Eneas and the Trojans to the Latin Shore,", 1859 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - "Our New Departed, A Staten Island View of Darwinism", 1872 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - "Page and His Works,", late1870s (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - On George Oakes Stevens, 1888 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - On Family History, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Miscellaneous Fragments, circa 1857, 1879, 1883, undated; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 8-9)
    - Sophia Page Journals, 1852-1853; (2 folders) (Box 5, Folder 10-11)
      (2 volumes, one with brief personal entries written in a bound and printed 1853 diary, the second with longer entries covering the same period in more detail)
    - Sophia Page Journal, 1853 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Sophia Page Journal, circa 1856, 1876 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Sophia Page Notebooks and Letterbooks, 1854 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Sophia Page Notebooks and Letterbooks, circa 1860s-1880s; (2 folders, including items found in book) (Box 5, Folder 15-16)
      (Large volume containing drafts of outgoing letters, essays, revisions of William Page writings, and possibly original writings on Swedenbourg and other subjects; at least one essay appears to be in William Page's handwriting, but the bulk of content is in Sophia Page's handwriting)
    - Translations of Classical Texts, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Notes (Box 5)
      - On David Hume's History of Britain, circa 1849 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Candace "Dacie" Page (daughter) Diary, 1884 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - George S. Page (son) Diary and Notebook, 1877-1878, 1882 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    (Diary details family life for the winter of 1877-1878)
  - Henry S. Page Poems, undated (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Sophia Stevens Page (daughter) Notebook, 1880-1883 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - William S. Page (son) Journal, 1882-1883 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Horace Stevens School Notebook, 1850; (Not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Stephen W. Hitchcock, 1843-1852, undated; (2 folders; not scanned) (Box 5, Folder 26-27)
  - J.T. Cobb, Notes on Bacon and Shakespeare, 1881 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - W.J. Linton, Notes on a Portrait, undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Other Authors, Manuscripts, 1852, 1865, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    (Handwritten manuscripts of John Brinsden's "Instructions for the Practice of the Grecian art of Painting in Dry Colors" and James Russell Lowell's "Mr. Hosea Biglow to the Editor of the Atlantic Monthly," as well as an unsigned, hand-painted booklet with religious verse)
  - Other Authors, Recipes for Shellac, Varnish, and Paint, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Collection Notes (Box 5)
    - Pauline Page Howell, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - James L. Page, undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Joshua Taylor, circa 1949 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Miscellaneous Prose, 1886, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Miscellaneous Poems, 1839, 1874, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Oversized Writings (Items scanned with Box 4, folders 29, 30, 42, 65, and 75) (Box 10 (OV))
- Personal Business Records, 1848-1932, undated; Series 4; (Boxes 5 and 9; 0.2 linear feet)
  This series contains bills, receipts, contracts, agreements, tax records, inventories, estate records, wills, memoranda, and legal records of William Page, Sophia Page, and family members and associates.